

Giacomo Di Biagio

Gender: Male | Phone number: (+33) 618015317 (Mobile) | Email address: dibiagio.giacomo@gmail.com

Website: https://giacomodibiagioportfolio.netlify.app/

Address: 116 Rue Caulaincourt, 75018, Paris, France (Home)

About me:

I'm Giacomo, a software developer based in Paris.

After completing my studies in Law I developed a strong passion for software engineering and I decided to build a career in this field.

With my leadership experience gathered over time, expecially working for Avanade and Tucoenergie, I am ready for a managerial or team-lead position where I can direct system testing and validation procedures, consult with departments or customers on project status and proposals, and work on technical issues including software system design and maintenance.

WORK EXPERIENCE

09/01/2023 - CURRENT Paris, France

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER TUCOENERGIE

I am responsible for using my knowledge of programming languages to design software programs that meet the needs of clients. I work with teams of coders to create websites, updating end-user softwares and conducting quality control functions.

TECH STACK: HTML, CSS, JS, TS (React), Versioning (GitHub, GitLab), Azure devops, Figma.

16/05/2022 - 31/12/2022 Rome, Italy

SENIOR FRONT END DEVELOPER AVANADE

I'm employed by Avanade, currently working as a senior front end developer for the italian biggest telco company, mainly focusing on the following area:

- Led the development of sophisticated Angular applications using micro frontends (mfe) architecture to enhance modularity and scalability.
- Conducted a comprehensive frontend refactoring and spearheaded the development of new, sophisticated components to enhance the application's performance and usability TECH STACK: HTML, CSS, JS, TS (Angular), Versioning (GitHub, GitLab).

01/07/2022 - CURRENT Rome, Italy

FRONT END DEVELOPER (MOBILE AND WEB) FREELANCE

While working for Avanade, I am also working as a freelance software engineer for Italian and European companies in the field of car sharing, mainly focusing on the following areas:

- Android, iOS, web development with Ionic Framework
- Frontend refactoring, development of new components, development of new features

TECH STACK: HTML, CSS, JS, TS (Angular, Ionic), Versioning (GitHub, GitLab).

01/01/2022 - 15/05/2022 Italy

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER FREELANCE

I worked as a freelance software engineer for many Italian and European companies, mainly focusing on the following area:

- Frontend refactoring and development of new components
- Unit and e2e testing
- Development of (micro)services using Spring Boot
- Refactoring of backend monolithic application

TECH STACK: Java (Spring), Javascript (Angular), SQL (MySql), Versioning (GitHub, GitLab).

01/01/2021 - 31/12/2021 Rome, Italy

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER SOLVING TEAM SRL

I worked as a full stack developer for Solving Team, a consultancy firm based in Rome. In this position I focused on the revamp of the web platform of the Italian Ministry of Economic and Finance. Focus area:

- Migration from monolith to micro services architecture more than 15 services extracted.
- Database refactoring and monitoring average time to guery reduced by 21%
- Migration of the frontend from jQuery to Angular
- Increased frontend test coverage from 32% to 65%

TECH STACK: Java (Spring Boot), Javascript (jQuery, Angular), CSS (Bootstrap), SQL (MySQL), Versioning (GitHub, GitLab).

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

16/05/2022 - CURRENT

ANGULAR BOOTCAMP C/O AVANADE - CORSO DI FABIO BIONDI

Website www.avanade.com

01/09/2020 - 31/12/2020

FULLSTACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER C/O SOLVING TEAM Solving Team srl

Website www.solvingteam.it

01/01/2021 - 31/12/2022

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Universitas Mercatorum

Website www.unimercatorum.it

01/01/2008 - 31/12/2013

JURIS DOCTOR Università degli studi Roma Tre

Website www.uniroma3.it

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): ITALIAN

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C2	C2	C1	C1	C1
FRENCH	C1	C1	C1	C1	C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user